G.S.M: +234-8037252747

e-mail: olaabolade@gmail.com

Address:

4, Alhaji Jalaga Street, Akala Way, Oluyole Extension,

Ibadan, Nigeria

AWS Security Engineer Olatilewa Raphael ABOLADE

Objectives

I have three years' experience with AWS resource management and have created several networks driving information management strategy, strategized, designed, and deployed innovative security architecture for cloud data protection. I am seeking an environment where I can use my understanding of Amazon Web Services global infrastructure and service migration and also sharpen my skills to be a topnotch solution Engineer. I have over 14 years' experience of Linux Administration and two years of AIX system Administration.

Skills

AWS Security engineer, Redhat Linux certified, installation, configuration and network management.

Work Experience

Freelance Linux and AWS Security Engineer

February 2013 to Date

Tasks

- •AWS Security workload Reviews and Configuration of services
- •AWS Cloud Migration
- •AWS Cloud Resource Management using AWS AIM, AWS CloudWatch, AWS CloudFormation and Auto Scaling.
- •Monitored existing infrastructure and architectural frameworks for performance, and made changes and updates when necessary.
- •Designed and edited blueprints for information Technology infrastructure and networking architecture according to client's needs with AWS.
- •Installation and administration and upgrade of Redhat Linux operating systems
- •Monitor servers (Linux and MySQL) using Nagios and SNORT
- •Configuration of services, devices and applications of Unix servers
- Running Backup Strategies using cron.

• Excellent communication skills and closely worked with different teams, developers and project leads.

Linux Systems Administrator

Fenix Limited 34, Coca-Cola Road, 1st Floor, Providence Court. Ibadan, Nigeria June 2008 to February 2013

Responsibilities:

- •Handled the installation and administration and upgrade of Redhat Linux operating systems
- •Performed disk management, creating and managing volume groups.
- •Configured volume groups and logical volumes, extended logical volumes for file systems growth needs using Logical Volume Managers (LVM).
- •Configured various services, devices and applications of Unix servers and worked with applications to customize the environment
- •Configured distributed file systems and administered BFS file systems and NFS Clients
- Scheduled data protection
- •Monitoring system health status and performance
- Running Backup Strategies using cron and responsible for managing cron jobs.
- Administration of different applications, Application performance monitoring, deploying.
- Actively involved in monitoring server performance, network traffic to reduce performance bottleneck by enhanced performance.

IBM Systems Engineer

Aira Technologies Limited, 206B, Muri-Okunola Street Victoria Island, Lagos, Nigeria. 2006 to 2008

Responsibilities:

- •Handled the installation and administration of AIX 5L V5.3 and Windows 2000 Server on the IBM BladeCenter JS20 using Serial Over LAN (SOL), and IBM BladeCenter JS21 and JS22 using IBM Director.
- •Installed and configured IBM Director Server, Console and Agent.
- •Carried out several New, Overwrite and Upgrade AIX installations on IBM system p/AIX and on-site support personel for Nseries storage devices at FirstInland(Fin) Bank, United Bank for Africa in Lagos.

- Planned, Designed, and implemented Hardware and Software Upgrades.
- Handled the tasks of training end-users/customers in the use of Windows software, Internet applications.
- Responsible for configuration of hardware for PCs and provided user support.
- Provided technical support, consulting with staff to identify and resolve problems with PC hardware, software, printing and network issues.
- Support personnel for customers on technical matters relating to pseries issues.
- If unable to resolve an issue, collects and documents necessary information for the appropriate specialist or higher-level personnel.
- Maintained and Performed System Backups.

Education

Master's degree in Computer Science, University of Ibadan, Nigeria. Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Nigeria.

Educational Summary and Certifications:

- Master's degree in Computer Science, University of Ibadan, Nigeria. 2012
- Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso. 2005
- Linux Certified System Administrator.2006

Membership of Professional Bodies

Linux Professional Institute, Ontario, Canada. 2006

Computer Professionals of Nigeria .2009